When you purchase a health insurance
policy in your name or in the name of your family,
you need to
know a lot of information before purchasing a health insurance policy. It should
not happen that you have
purchased a health insurance policy today
and for some reason when you have a
claim,
the claim is rejected by the company. It may be that there
was no pre-existing rejection in your policy. It may be that
you do not know about the waiting period in your policy. There is a
limitation or treatment. So there are
many types of treatments or
benefits. Those benefits are
written in your policy but there are limitations
or limitations. So what will happen in that case?
If you do not have any claim now, but if you do have a
claim at that time, the amount of your claim will be
less. So let's
now ask 10 questions and with them  Along with the
answers, I will know the ten questions and
answers that you must definitely know
before purchasing a health policy. When we compare any health
insurance policy, the first question that
comes to our mind is how much coverage we will take or whether we will take a short-term contract.
It will depend
on your location, the city you are living in,
how much the city costs, and along with this,
it will also depend on
how much you have the ability to pay the premium
or whether you can actually pay that premium or
not, and along with this,
what lifestyle you lead, you
can take a similar policy coverage and
I will recommend you that
according to today's expenses and along with this, you will
see that the health insurance policy has a capping or limitation
if you have a minimum of 10 lakh taka.  If you
take a policy with shots, then there is
no capping in the maximum policy, so you will try to
take a minimum of 10 lakh taka cement shot,
but if your lifestyle is a little high
profile or if you can afford the
premium or
if you can deposit the premium, then of
course you will have more coverage, but you will
keep it more. This will depend on your
ability to deposit the premium and your
lifestyle. Next question, let's look at
question number two. Will
you take the policy just for yourself or for your family? I mean, you are thinking of purchasing a health policy,
but you will do that policy in your own name
or in the name of your family.
If this thought
comes to your mind, then I want to tell you that
health insurance policy means
health insurance. This health insurance or
health car will go bad, but you don't know when it will go bad.
I don't know either. It may be
that you have two adults and one child, then
you will only have two children.  You have taken
coverage in the name of the adult and the child may not have been
admitted to the children's hospital and all your money has been
spent. So I will tell you that it will
depend on you. If you
want to cover the entire family through one premium,
then you
should definitely go for a floater plan or a family floater
plan. If you
have less ability to pay premium and
you want only you to be secure,
then you can take an individual or self policy.
I
want to explain to you one difference between this family floater and individual policy. Look,
I have assumed here that you have two adults,
one child and
two parents in your house. In that case,
if you
want to cover the entire family
member through a single premium with these five people, then the premium that will be
charged here is the highest age that
you have.  The
premium will be
calculated depending on the highest age of the parents and the number of years they are living in the house. So I will tell you that
if you have children in your house
and you live with them and you have any
parents, then you will try to
add them with your children and give
separate policies to your parents. The
premium will be a little less. And if you
take a separate policy, then see. I am assuming that
if you take a policy of 10 lakhs, then
you and your wife
and along with that, your children will
get coverage of 10 lakhs and your parents will also
get coverage of 10 lakhs. And
if you do not do this, if you take a submission of 10 lakhs with all these five people, then
all five people will
get coverage of 10 lakhs and if you do this in parts,
then the premium will be a little less.
Along with that, you will get coverage of 10 lakhs and 10 lakhs.
So I hope you understand
that when you have any kind of  When
purchasing a health insurance policy, do
not take it as a single policy,
try to purchase a policy as a family floater. The
reason for purchasing a family floater policy is that no one knows what will happen to anyone in your family
and
if you have less ability to pay the premium
or if you cannot pay the premium, then
you should definitely purchase a
health insurance policy in your own name.
Later, you can also add it
to your policy. Let's see the next question.
Many people ask this question, when should
we purchase a health insurance policy?
Right age to buy a health insurance policy.
Friends, today there is no
date for purchasing a health insurance policy.
Friends, you cannot say who will be affected when.
Even a small child has a heart
attack. So I will tell you that you should
definitely buy a health insurance policy at a young age
because something like this can happen
to you.  I don't
know if it will happen tomorrow, you don't know either, so for
accidental purposes, something can happen then,
so I will tell you that you have the
ability to pay the premium, but you should definitely
purchase a health policy,
but don't wait, let's say
five years from today or
three years from today. Let's look at the right next question.
Question number four: Should you take the
premium for a chip policy? You will see that there are
many people who are looking for a chip policy
and what should be done with the chip premium.
I want to explain to you with an example.
This is Company A
and this is Company B. I am assuming that
you two adults are taking a submit
shot together. Company A is charging 10 lakh taka,
let's say ৳10,000 taka, Company
B is charging 20,000 taka, in
that case, you should not take the policy in Company A or
Company B. When such a
condition arises, you will have to
judge some things or compare some things.
So the
first thing you will do is compare the benefits of the plan that will be given to you.
What are the benefits in company
number A and company number B?
Then you will see about this company.
What is the claim settlement ratio in this company number?
What are the network hospitals?
About claim
settlement. You will see what is the claim settlement
ratio in company number B? What are the network hospitals?
You should go to which company after considering all these. But keep in mind
that cheap is not
always good. Cheap things are not always good. So it may happen to you
that you have taken a policy in company number A because of
low premium. At
the last moment, you saw that there
was a co-payment there when you took the claim. For example, if you have a
claim of one lakh taka, the company has to pay
40,000 taka. The remaining
৳60,000 taka has to be paid from your pocket. The
room rate limit is ৳5,000
taka per day limit, but where
you were admitted to the room, where you were admitted,  If it is
giving ৳10000 per day, then
you have to pay ৳5000
from your pocket. The reason is that you are purchasing a health policy
that is not useful to you in times of danger. When
you go to claim during a time of danger, the company
says that there were these limits with me, but you did
not see them when you took the policy.
So I hope you understand. Next
question number five is to check the room rail
limit in your policy. This is a very
vital thing. Why am I saying vital, friends? I assume that
you have taken a 10 lakh taka sumain
short right from some
XYZ company and it is written in that policy that
if you take a 10 lakh taka sumain short,
then 1% of the sum and
short will cover you. As a room rate limit,
see that 1% of that 10 lakh taka means
৳10000 taka as the room rate limit.
But the company will pay and you
have such a nursing admission there
but per day.  There is a room rate limit of 20000 taka, it may be, so
see that the remaining
10000 taka is not a room line limit,
but you will have to pay it from your pocket,
so before or while taking a health insurance policy, you must definitely
know
what is the status of the room rail limit in your policy.
If you see that the room rail limit is
low, then you should definitely
skip it. You should
take a policy where the room rate limit is
unlimited. As I was saying,
some policies have 1% as this room rate limit,
some policies have 2%, some policies have AC
single private standard room, some
policies have no room rate limit. Next, I will
go to question number six. You must know the
waiting period after how long it will
cover which diseases. So friends, see
this waiting period is the biggest vital
chapter. Waiting while purchasing a health research policy.
Period means that
you have purchased the policy today and
all diseases will not be covered from one day onwards.
But there is a period
after that period,
if something happens to your patient or if something happens to you, the
company will pay,
otherwise it will not pay in any way.
See the company. The initial waiting period of a health insurance
policy is 30
days. Suppose you have purchased the policy today from day one.
If you are admitted due to an accidental related reason, the
company will be paid. After that, there is an
initial waiting period of 30
days. If you have purchased the policy today, after 30 days
you are present in the hospital and are
admitted to the hospital 24 hours a day,
then the company will pay and it must be
non-surgical. It can be
dengue fever, malaria, etc. Then see the
specified disease. There are all kinds of specified diseases,
for example, all the
diseases that take a little time to develop, such as
goiter, ENT, eye,
ear.  Throat hernia, piles, fistula, these are the
diseases that you did not have and if it
is direct after two years of the policy, then the
company will be paid and many times it does
not happen that at the time of taking the policy, you
had a certain disease or a certain
percentage had this disease to the company
but you showed that disease, so the
company says that we will cover all those diseases,
but after three years of taking the policy,
it is called pre-existing disease,
but they will cover them. Along with this,
some policies also have maternity cover
that covers one year of taking the policy and two years of taking the policy, there is also
newborn baby cover, so
these are things. You have to take a look at
what is the waiting period in any policy.
Next, we will look at question number seven.
You must see the network hospital list.
When you purchase a policy from any company, then the
network hospital
list is there. But
you must definitely know where and what type of health insurance policy you have.  There
is a type with some nursing, so the
more hospitals in the company's network, the
more benefits you will
get for cashless treatment. And
another thing to remember is that the
health cell policy you buy should have its
own TPA, such as in-house
settlement, which does not have third-party
administration. The next question to
keep in mind is, does your policy cover all day care treatment?
Friends, sometimes there are some diseases that do
not require you to be hospitalized 24 hours a day, such as
cataract surgery. So when you
purchase a health research policy,
you also have to check whether that
policy covers every head care
treatment. Question
number nine: Does your policy cover all eye
treatment.
Nowadays, most policies provide
Ayush treatment coverage, and
most people these days,  Ayush
treatment also wants to be done. Ayush treatment
means Ayurveda, it can be yoga, it can be
naturopathy, it can be urani siddha,
homeopathy. So if you want to cover
your patient
or yourself through Ayush treatment, then
you can also take this treatment.
When you make your policy, health policy, then you will also take care of
this Ayush treatment.
Question number ten: Does
your policy cover refill benefit? Is this
refill benefit a refill benefit? I am
assuming that you have taken a sum assured of 10 lakhs in a
policy type of two adults and one
child. Suppose your claim is 2 lakhs. In
that case, where will your remaining sum assured be?
This remaining member will get 8 lakhs.
Or if you are admitted to the hospital again, you will
get coverage of this 8 lakhs. So,
if there is a refill benefit in your policy,  If
you have 8 lakhs and you claim 2 lakhs
automatically, the company will automatically refill this 2 lakhs, which
means 10 lakhs will be submitted
automatically. You must definitely check whether this is
in your policy
and also see whether it will cover the same illness and the
same percentage. If it does, then
you are definitely going towards a good
policy. But this is also a
big point that while making a policy, you must definitely know whether there is a
refill benefit or not.
These
were our ten questions, friends. I hope you
understood these questions. You must definitely
know when you purchase a health
insurance policy. And
with this, I want to give you some extra information.
That is, non-payable items.
Friends, some policies contain non-
payable items but do not cover them, such as cotton,
sis, bandages, etc.
So if your policy covers non-payable items,
then it is better to see if any of them are not
claimed at that time.
Nursing items cost a little more, so if your
policy covers non-payable items, the
company will pay for them. You will also see the no claim bonus.
If there is no claim every year, the
no claim bonus will increase by how much. It is also
very important to see the claim
settlement ratio. You also need to see
what the claim settlement ratio is of the insurance company from which you are taking the policy. You do not need to know how many claims they are able to settle. You will also
see how pre and post hospitalization
works. For example, if a
person is admitted to the hospital and the
expenses incurred in the 60 days before admission to the hospital, the
company will pay for them and the expenses incurred after release. So,
you will see that the pre and post
hospitalization period is 90 days and the
post hospitalization period is 180 days. If this is the case, then
your policy will definitely cover you.  It's going to be the
best, so I hope you understand
which questions
you absolutely must know the answers to when you
purchase a health insurance policy. If you like the
video, like it, if you're
new, subscribe, keep
watching, thank you, Namaskar Allah.